big5sportinggoods.com 2017-12-07

# Privacy Policy | Big 5 Sporting Goods

  * home >
  * privacy policy

Protecting your privacy is important to us. Accordingly, we’re providing this Privacy Policy to explain our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive when you use our Services (as defined in our Terms of Service accessible at Terms of Service . This Privacy Policy applies only to those websites, services and applications included within “Services” and doesn’t apply to any third-party websites, services or applications, even if they are accessible through our Services. Such third-party websites, services or applications are conducted in accordance with their own completely separate privacy practices, which Big 5 does not endorse or control. Also, please note that, unless we define a term in this Privacy Policy, all capitalized words used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service.

###  How Do We Collect And Use Information?

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Services, to administer your use of the Services (including your Account, if you are an Account holder), and to enable you to enjoy and easily navigate our Services.

**Account Information.** When you create an Account, we’ll collect certain information that can be used to identify you, such as your name and email address (“ **Personally Identifiable Information** ” or “ **PII** ”). We will also collect certain PII from you if you decide to purchase a product through our Services, such as your phone number, credit card number, billing address and shipping address. When you engage in certain activities via the Services, such as, without limitation, registering for e-mail promotions or notifications, participating in contests, sweepstakes, or our league loyalty program, setting up a shopping cart or Wishlist, ordering a gift card, requesting donations, or submitting an online form, you may be asked to provide PII. Depending on the activity in which you engage, such PII may be required or optional.

We may also collect certain information that is not PII because it cannot be used by itself to identify you, such as your date of birth and shopping interests (e.g., whether your interests are with camping & hiking, hunting & fishing, and/or fitness, etc.).

**E-Team Program.** If you agree to receive email or “special offers” from us when you sign up for an Account, sign up for our E-Team, or otherwise consent to receiving email from us, we may, from time to time, send you emails regarding our products and services. Only Big 5, or third parties working on our behalf, will send you these emails. If you do not want to receive these emails anymore you can unsubscribe by following the unsubscribe option in the email. If you encounter difficulties unsubscribing, please contact "Feedback" at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#80e6e5e5e4e2e1e3ebc0e2e9e7b5e3eff2f0aee3efedbff3f5e2eae5e3f4bdc6e5e5e4e2e1e3eba0e6f2efeda0e2e9e7b5f3f0eff2f4e9eee7e7efefe4f3aee3efedbff3f5e2eae5e3f4baa0c6e5e5e4e2e1e3eba0e1f4a0e2e9e7b5f3f0eff2f4e9eee7e7efefe4f3aee3efeda0ada0d0e8e9f3e8e9eee7).

**Purchase History.** If you create an Account, in addition to collecting and storing Log Data (defined below), we may also store certain information that you provided in connection with completing your purchase via the Services (e.g., your purchase history and certain billing information). We reserve the right to keep such information as long as we have a legal use for the same, subject to the terms of our retention policy.

**Information Collected Using Cookies.** We collect certain information through the use of “cookies,” which are small text files that are saved by your browser when you access our Services. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to identify that you’ve logged in to the Services and to tell us how and when you interact with our Services. We may also use cookies to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on our Services and to customize and improve our Services. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted when you log off from the Services and close your browser. Although most browsers automatically accept cookies, you can change your browser options to stop automatically accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting cookies. Please note, however, that if you don’t accept cookies, you may not be able to access all portions or features of the Services. Some third-party services providers that we engage (including third-party advertisers) may also place their own cookies on your browser. Note that this Privacy Policy covers only our use of cookies and does not include use of cookies by such third parties. Such third-party cookies are conducted in accordance with their own completely separate privacy practices.

**Information Related to Use of the Services.** Our servers automatically record certain information about how Users use our Services (we refer to this information as “Log Data”). Log Data may include information such as, but not limited to, a User’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, operating system, the web page that a User was visiting before accessing our Services, the pages or features of our Services to which a User browsed and the time spent on those pages or features, search terms, the links on our Services that a User clicked on and other statistics. We use this information to administer the Services and we analyze (and may engage third parties to analyze) this information to improve and enhance the Services, including, for example, by expanding their features and functionality and tailoring them to our Users’ needs and preferences. We may use a person’s IP address to fight spam, malware and identity theft. We also use the IP Address to generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how our Services are used.

**Location Information.** In some cases we may collect and store information about where you are located, such as by converting your IP address into a rough geolocation. We may use location information to improve and personalize our Services for you.

**Information Collected Via Email.** We will also receive PII about you if you send us an email and we’ll use that PII in order to respond to your email communication.

###  What Information Do We Share With Third Parties?

We will not share any PII that we have collected from you except as described below:

**Information Shared with Our Services Providers.** We may engage third party service providers to work with us to administer and provide the Services (“Third Party Providers”). Such Third Party Providers include, but are not limited to, payment and sales tax processing service providers, web hosting service providers and data analytics service providers. These Third Party Providers have access to your PII for the purposes of performing services on our behalf.

**Information Shared with Third Parties.** We may share aggregated information and non-identifying information with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other similar purposes.

**Information Disclosed in Connection with Business Transactions.** Information that we collect from our users, including PII, is considered to be a business asset. As a result, if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy or if we are acquired as a result of a transaction such as a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your PII may be disclosed or transferred to the third-party acquirer in connection with the transaction.

**Information Disclosed for Our Protection and the Protection of Others.** It is our policy to protect you from having your privacy violated through abuse of the legal systems, whether by individuals, entities or government, and to contest claims that we believe to be invalid under applicable law. However, it is also our policy to cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties. Accordingly, we reserve the right to disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe appropriate: (i) to satisfy or comply with any applicable law, regulation or legal process or to respond to lawful requests, including subpoenas, warrants or court orders; (ii) to protect our property, rights and safety and the rights, property and safety of third parties or the public in general; and (iii) to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

**Information We Disclose With Your Consent or at Your Request.** We may share your PII with third-party sites or platforms if you have expressly requested that we do so.

**Information Shared Within Big 5.** We may share information we collect about you, including your PII, with our affiliates and subsidiaries only in order to provide our Services.

**Sharing Your Wishlist.** You may create a “Wishlist” via your Account on the Services and you may share your Wishlist, via the Services. In order to do so, you will provide us with the email addresses with those persons with whom you would like to share your Wishlist. We will use these email addresses for the sole purposes of sharing your Wishlist and for no other purposes.

###  The Security of Your Information

We take reasonable measures to protect the information that we collect from or about you (including your PII) from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of any information.

While we try to protect the information that we collect, you should also take measures to protect your information. This includes ensuring that your password and computer is protected against unauthorized access. You must also select a strong password, and never divulge your username or password to anyone. For additional security, you may want to change your password periodically. When using a shared computer, be sure to sign-off when finished and delete any stored personal information on the shared computer.

Note: “Phishing” is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an e-mail that looks like it might be from us asking for your personal information, do not respond. We would not and will not request your password, user name, credit card information, or other personal information through e-mail. Please report all “ phishing” attempts to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d9bfbcbcbdbbb8bab299bbb0beecbab6aba9f7bab6b4e6aaacbbb3bcbaade49fbcbcbdbbb8bab2f9bfabb6b4f9bbb0beecaaa9b6abadb0b7bebeb6b6bdaaf7bab6b4e6aaacbbb3bcbaade3f99fbcbcbdbbb8bab2f9b8adf9bbb0beecaaa9b6abadb0b7bebeb6b6bdaaf7bab6b4f9f4f989b1b0aab1b0b7be).

###  Links to Other Sites

Our Services may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or services and we’re not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of those websites or services. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access.

###  Modifying Your Information

You can access and modify the PII associated with your Account by signing in to your Account and following the instructions for making such modifications via the Services. You may change most of your PII (but not, for example, change your username) associated with your online account. If you are unable to access and/or change your Personally Identifiable Information, please contact "Feedback" at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#27414242434546444c67454e4012444855570944484a185452454d4244531a614242434546444c074155484a07454e401254574855534e494040484843540944484a).

###  International Transfer

Your PII may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you’re located outside the United States and choose to provide your PII to us, we may transfer your PII to the United States and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of any PII represents your agreement to that transfer.

###  Our Policy Toward Children

Our Services are not directed to people under 18 and we do not knowingly collect PII from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected PII from a child under 13 we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible. If you are a parent or guardian who knows or has discovered that your child under the age of 18 has submitted his or her Personally Identifiable Information or other information without your consent, permission or authorization, please notify us by sending an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6e080b0b0a0c0f0d052e0c07095b0d011c1e400d0103511d1b0c040b0d1a53280b0b0a0c0f0d054e081c01034e0c07095b1d1e011c1a0700090901010a1d400d0103) or a letter to:

Big 5 Sporting Goods  
Attn: Web Support  
2525 East El Segundo Boulevard  
El Segundo, California 90245

Upon receiving such a notice, we will take steps to: (a) notify you what information may have been used and/or disclosed; and (b) remove your child’s Personally Identifiable Information or other information from our databases, cease the use of such information, and direct any other party with access to such information to do the same.

###  Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any information that we collect is subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time such information is collected. We may, however, modify and revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we’ll notify you of such changes by posting them on the Services or by sending you an email or other notification, and we’ll indicate when such changes will become effective.

###  Questions?

Please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e98f8c8c8d8b888a82a98b808edc8a869b99c78a8684d69a9c8b838c8a9dd4af8c8c8d8b888a82c98f9b8684c98b808edc9a99869b9d80878e8e86868d9ac78a8684) if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy.

###  California Do Not Track Disclosures

For information on “ **Your California Privacy Rights** ” please see below:

Under California’s "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us (once a calendar year) certain information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2014 will receive information regarding 2013 sharing activities).

To obtain this information on behalf of Big 5 Corp. please send an email message to Customer Service at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4f292a2a2b2d2e2c240f2d26287a2c203d3f612c2022703c3a2d252a2c3b72092a2a2b2d2e2c246f293d20226f2d26287a3c3f203d3b2621282820202b3c612c2022) with "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the "Shine the Light" requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

Alternatively, you may request the above information by sending a letter to:

Big 5 Sporting Goods  
Attn: Web Support (Your California Privacy Rights)  
2525 East El Segundo Boulevard  
El Segundo, California 90245

For all letter requests, include your full name, street address, city, state and zip code. If you have previously furnished an email address to us, or have registered on our Sites, please provide your email address and registration info as well (do NOT provide your password to us). In the subject line of your request you should state that it is regarding “Request for California Privacy Information”.
